Labor Leader Biographies 5211
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Labor Leader Biographies
1873-2010
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Kheel Center
5211
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Biography (genre).
Biographical data on various individuals prominent in labor unions in the United States since 1910.
5555878
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 14, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 21, 2017
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of biographical data on various individuals prominent in labor unions in the United States since 1910. Includes articles, clippings, pamphlets, vita, obituaries and manuscript notes, filed alphabetically by name of individual.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780/177: ILGWU Communications Department Biography Files
Abbott, William L., 1925-; Abel, Gorwith Wilbur; Allen, Walter M. 1914-; Antonini, Luigi, 1883-1968.; Baldanzi, George, 1907- 1972; Barkan, Alexander E.; Bates, Harry C.; Beck, Dave, 1894-1993; Beirne, Joseph A., 1911-; Birthright, William C. 1887-; Brady, Joseph E.; Brewster, Frank W.; Brown, Wlmer, -1968; Buckmaster, L.S.; Burdon, George; Burke, John P., 1884-; Burnell, William H., 1892-; Campbell, James; Carey, James B., 1911-; Clay, John G., -1928; Corbett, Raymond R., 1915-; Crotty, Harold C. (Harold Clifford), 1911-; Curran, Joseph, 1906-; Dalton, Howard R.; DeAndrade, Anthony J.; Doherty, William C. (William Charles), 1902-1987; Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982; Elliot, John M., 1913-; Feller, Karl F., 1914-; Freeman, Gordon M.; Furuseth, Andres, 1854-1938; Gianini, Mildred, 1899-; Gilbert, H.E., 1906-; Gildea, Arthur P.; Gill, William A.; Hampton, M.W., 1980-; Harrison, George M. (George McGregor); Hayes, Albert J. (Albert John), 1900-1981; Heath, Perry S., 1899-; Hillman, Sidney, 1887-1946; Hoffa, James; Hollander, Louis, 1893-; Hutcheson, Maurice A., 1897-; Jodoin, Claude, 1913-; Keenan, Joseph C., 1896-; Kennedy, Thomas, 1887-; Knight, O.A.; Kralshein, Max; Kramer, Leon, 1889-1962; Lauterbach, Harvey; Lewis, John L. (John Llewellyn), 1880-1969.; Meany, George, 1894-1980; Fetridge, William L.; Minton, Lee W., 1911-; Mischo, O.J., 1904-; Mollin, P.J., 1879-1951; MacGowan, Charles, 1887-; McDonald, David J. (David John), 1902-1979; O'Brien, Harry, 1919-; Olander, Victor, 1874-1949; Oliver, Edward W., 1914-; Owens, John; Azpeitia, Mario; Perlis, Leo, 1912- 1986; Petrillo, James C. (James Caesar), 1892-1984; Phillips, Paul L., 1904-; Pollock, William, 1899-; Potofsky, Jacob S. (Jacob Samuel), 1894-1979; Powers, Bertram; Raferty, L.M., 1895-; Randolph, Philip A., 1889-; Randolph, Woodruff, 1892-1966; Reuther, Walter, 1907-1970; Rieve, Emil, 1892-1975; Rosenblum, Frank, 1888-1973; Rusch, Thomas; Ryan, Joseph P. (Joseph Patrick), 1884-1963; Schnitzler, William P., 1904-; Schoemann, Peter T., 1893-; Smith, Thomas W., 1906-; Spiers, Neil P., 1912-; Starr, Mark, 1894-1985; Suffridge, James A.; Sullivan, David, 1904-; Townsend, William S., 1900-; Whitney, Alexander F. (Alexander Fell), 1873-1949; Winter, Herman, 1884-; Woll, Matthew, 1880-1956; Zumach, Gilbert; Kheel Center for Labor-Management and Documentations and Archives
5555878
- Biographies of Prominent Individuals in Labor Unions since 1910 (Box 1)
  - Abbot, William L. United Rubber Workers, Education Director (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abel, Gorwith Wilbur, United Steelworkers, President (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Allen, Walter M., International Printing Pressmen and Assistants Union, Service Bureau Director, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Scope and Contents
    (b. 1914 - d. )
  - Antonini, Luigi, International Ladies Garment Workers Union, Vice President (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Baldanzi, George, United Textile Workers of America, President, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    (b. 1907)
  - Barkan, Alexander E., American Federation of Labor - Congress of industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), Committee on Political Education, Director (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bates, Harry C. Bricklayers, Masons and Plasterers International Union of America, President (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Beck, David, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, President, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    (b. 1894)
  - Beirne, Joseph A., Communication Workers of America, International President (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Birthright, William C., Journeyman Barbers, Hairdressers and Cosmetologists International Union, General President, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    (b. 1887)
  - Brady, Joseph E. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Brewster, Frank W., Western Conference of Teamsters, Vice President (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Brown, Elmer, International Typographical Union, President (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Buckmaster, L.S., United Rubber Workers, President (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Burdon, George, United Rubber Workers International Union, President, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    (b. 1909)
  - Burke, John P., International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite, and Paper Mill Workers (IBPSPMW), President, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    (b. 1884)
  - Burnell, William H., IBPSMW, President, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    (b. 1892)
  - Campbell, James, American Federation of Government Employees, President (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Carey, James B., AFL-CIO, Vice President, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    (b 1911)
  - Clay, John G., Laundry and Dye House Drivers Union #712, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Secretary-Treasurer, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    (d. 1928)
  - Corbett, Raymond R., New York State AFL-CIO, President, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    (b. 1915)
  - Crotty, Harold C., Brotherhood of Maintenance Way Employees, President, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    (b. 1911)
  - Curran, Joseph, National Maintenance Union, President, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    (b. 1906)
  - Dalton, Howard R., International Union of Operating Engineers, President (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - De Andrade, Anthony J., International Printing, Pressmen and Assistants Union of North America, President (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Doherty, William C., National Association of Letter Carriers, President, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    (b. 1902)
  - Dubinsky, David, ILGWU, President, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Elliot, John M., Amalgamated Transit Union, International President, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    (b. 1913)
  - Feller, Karl F., International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink and Distillery Workers, President, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    (b. 1914)
  - Freeman, Gordon M., International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, International President (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Furuseth, Andrew, International Seaman's Union of America, President (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Gianini, Mildred, International Union of Cleaning and Dye Workers, Secretary Treasurer, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    (b. 1899)
  - Gilbert, H.E., Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, President, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Gildea, Arthur P., AFL-CIO, Secretary Treasurer (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Gill, William A, Flight Engineers International Association, President (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Hampton, M.W., Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, Assistant President, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    (b. 1980)
  - Harrison, George M., AFL-CIO, Vice President, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    (b. 1895)
  - Hayes, Albert J., International Association of Machinists, Vice President, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    (b. 1900)
  - Heath, Perry S., Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers, Grand Chief Engineer, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Hillman, Sidney, Amalgamated Clothing Workers, President, 1887-1946 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    (b. 1887, d. 1946)
  - Hoffa, James, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, President (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Hollander, Louis, New York State Council of the CIO, President, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    (b. 1893)
  - Hutcheson, Maurice A., United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, General President, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    (b. 1897)
  - Jodoin, Claude, Canadian Labor Congress, President, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Keenan, Joseph C., IBEW, International Secretary, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    (b. 1896)
  - Kennedy, Thomas, United Mine Workers of America, Vice President, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Knight, O.A., Oil, Chemical, and Atomic Workers Union, President (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Kralshein, Max, Bakery, Confectionary Workers, President (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Meany, George, AFL-CIO, President, 1894-1980 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    (b. 1894, d. 1980)
  - McFetridge, William L. Building Service Employees International Union, President (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Minton, Lee W., Glass and Bottle Blowers Association, International President, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Mischo, O.J., Amalgamated Transit Union, International Secretary Treasurer, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    (b. 1904)
  - Mollin, P.J., Iron Workers International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers, President, 1879-1951 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - MacGowan, Charles, AFLCIO, Vice President, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - McDonald, David J., United Steelworkers of America, President, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - O'Brien, Harry, Flight Engineers International Association, Executive Vice President, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    (b. 1919)
  - Olander, Victor, Sailors Union of the Great Lakes, General Secretary, 1874-1949 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Oliver, Edward M., Amalgamated Transit Union, General Executive Board Member, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Owens, John, United Mine Workers, Secretary-Treasurer (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Ozpeitia, Mario, Cigar Makers International Union, President (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Perlis, Leo, AFL-CIO, Community Services Activity, National Director (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Petrillo, James C., American Federation of Musicians, President, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Phillips, Paul L., United Papermakers and Paperworker, International President (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Pollock, William, Textile Workers Union of America, President (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Potofsky, Jacob S., Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, General President, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Powers, Bertram, International Typographical Union, Local 6, President (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Raferty, L.M., AFL-CIO, Building Trades Department, Vice President, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Randolph, Phillip A., International Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters, President, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Randolph, Woodruff, Typographical Union, Chicago #16, President (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Reuther, Walter P.,United Auto Workers, President, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Rieve, Emil, Textile Workers Union of America, General President, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Rosenlum, Frank, Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, General Secretary Treasurer, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    (b. 1888)
  - Rusch, Thomas, Brewery Workers, General Secretary-Treasurer (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Ryan, Joseph P., Long Shoremans Union, International President, 1884-1963 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Schnitzler, William P., Bakery and Confectionary Workers International Union, President, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Schoemann, Peter T., United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry of the United States and Canada, President, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Smith, Thomas W., Specialty Worker Paper, Printing Specialities, and Paper Products Local 612, Editor and Manager, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Speirs, Neil P., Switchmens Union of North America, President, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    (b. 1912)
  - Starr, Mark, ILGWU, Education Director (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Suffridge, James A. AFL-CIO, Vice President (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Sullivan, David, Building Service Employees International Union, President (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Townsend, William S., United Transport Service Employees, President, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Whitney, Alexander, Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, President, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    (b. 1873)
  - Winter, Herman, Bakery and Confectionary Workers of America, President, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Woll, Matthew, AFL-CIO, Vice President, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    (b. 1880)
  - Zumach, Gilbert, Technicians Engineers Association, President (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Kheel, Theodore W., 1989-2010 (Box 1, Folder 87)